American Brass Company Records 1997.0996
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series VIII: Bound Volumes, undated, 1823-1972
  - Coe Brass Manufacturing Co.
    - General & Purchase Ledger (and Index), 1901-1905 (Volume V.91)
  - Connecticut Mining Co.
    - Ledger “A”, 1853-1859 (Volume V.92)
    - Journal “A”, 1853-1863 (Volume V.93)
  - Detroit & Lake Superior Copper Co.
    - Cash Book “A”, 1868-1893 (Volume V.94)
    - Ledger “A”, 1867-1879 (Volume V.95)
    - Journal “A”, 1867-1883 (Volume V.96)
  - Detroit Copper & Brass Rolling Mills
    - Corporate Record, 1910-1920 (Box 97)
    - Corporate Record, 1920-1927
    - Corporate Record, 1927-1934
    - Corporate Record (Inc.?), 1920-1921
    - Cancelled Stock Certificates, 1928
  - Elton Banking Co.
    - Corporate Record, 1865-1877
  - French Manufacturing Co.
    - Corporate Record, 1905-1929
    - Corporate Record, 1929-1962
    - “General Ledger”, 1950
    - Cancelled Stocks, 1906-1962
  - Holmes, Hotchkiss, Brown & Elton
    - Cash Book, 1835 (Box 98)
  - Holmes, Booth and Haydens
    - Day Book (“Blotter”), 1855-1857
    - Journal “A”, 1853-1857 (Volume V.99)
    - Journal “B”, 1856-1859 (Volume V.100)
    - Ledger, 1853-1856 (Volume V.101)
    - Cash Book #2, 1857-1860 (Volume V.102)
    - Day Book, 1853-1856 (Box 103)
    - Day Books, 1854-1855, 1858-1862 (Box 104)
  - Kenosha Brass Co.
    - Minutes, 1941-1950 (Box 105)
    - Minutes, 1950-1962
    - Minutes (dup.), 1951-1962
    - Cancelled Stock Certificates, 1941-1961
    - Duplicate Stock Ledger, 1941-1956
  - National Brass and Copper Tube Company, Inc.
    - Corporate Record, 1917-1925
  - Old Trails Realty Corp.
    - Corporate Record (missing volume), 1953
  - Portage Lake Smelting Works
    - Ledger “A”, 1860-1867 (Volume V.106)
    - Journal “A”, 1860-1866 (Volume V.107)
  - >The River Company
    - Ledger “A”, 1895-1900 (Volume V.108)
    - Journal “A”, 1894-1901 (Volume V.109)
  - Wallace and Sons
    - Minutes, 1853-1894 (Box 110)
  - Waterbury & Detroit Copper Co.
    - Dividend Book, 1863-1867
    - Cash Book, 1862-1867
    - Journal, 1864-1867
    - Ledger, 1864-1867
  - Waterbury Brass Co.
    - Corporate Record (Box 111)
      - “A”, 1845 April 1 - 1865 January 25
      - “B”, 1865 February 20 - 1873 May 7
      - “C”, 1871 January 5 - 1909 January 27
      - “D”, 1909 January 27 -1912
    - Stock Ledger, 1852-1889
    - Accounts Payable and Receivable, 1845-1851
    - Cancelled Stocks, 1870-1894
    - Payroll, 1847-1854
    - Payroll, 1859-1863
    - Payroll, 1915-1920
    - Journal (#1), 1900-1904
    - Ledger
      - “A”, 1845-1849 (Volume V.112)
      - “B”, 1850-1854 (Volume V.113)
      - “C”, 1853-1854 (Volume V.114)
      - “C”, 1853-1855 (Volume V.115)
    - Journal
      - “A”, 1845-1848 (Volume V.116)
      - “B”, 1847-1848 (Volume V.117)
      - “D”, 1850-1851 (Volume V.118)
      - “G”, 1854 (Volume V.119)
      - “I”, 1855-1856 (Volume V.120)
      - “J”, 1856-1857 (Volume V.121)
      - “U”, 1869-1870 (Volume V.122)
    - Balance Book, 1847-1880 (Box 123)
  - Waterbury Brass Goods Corp.
    - Minutes, 1904-1926
    - Minutes, 1927-1950
    - Minutes, 1951-1962
    - Cancelled Stocks, 1934-1962
  - Waterbury Homes Corp.
    - Minutes, 1916-1918
    - Minutes, 1925-1928
    - Minutes, 1929-1938
    - Journal, 1916-1919
    - Journal, 1920-1924
    - Journal, 1925-1949
    - Cash Book, 1916-1919
    - Cash Book, 1940-1949 (Box 124)
    - Ledger, 1937-1949
    - Cancelled Stocks, 1916-1938
    - Trial Balance, 1944-1949 (Volume V.125)
  - Waterbury Manufacturing Co.
    - Cash Book (“Wilmot Shop”), 1875-1881 (Box 126)
  - Wolcottville Brass Co.
    - Shareholder Register, 1841-1864
    - Inventory, 1841-1863
  - Unidentified Companies
    - Ledger, 1920-1924 (Box 127)
    - Ledger, 1925-1928
    - Ledger, 1931-1936
    - Ledger (“B&C Manufactory”), “B”, 1832-1835
    - Cash Book, 1920-1924
    - Cash Book, 1925-1928
    - Cash Book, 1932-1937
    - Share Register and Transfer Book, 1913-1920
    - Journal, 1850-1853 (Volume V.128)
    - Index, undated (Volume V.129)
    - Inventory, 1849 (Box 127)
    - Day Book, 1829-1830 (Box 130)
    - Day Book, 1829-1832
    - General Ledger Index, 1912-1917 (?) (Box 131)
    - General Ledger Index, undated (Box 132)
      Papers Stored with Bound Volumes
      These loose papers were removed from the bound volumes of the American Brass Company. They are currently stored alongside of the originating company records. Of interest are those papers from the American Brass Association, stored with the Waterbury Brass Co. papers. Unarranged.
  - American Brass Company
    - Stockholder Notes, 1900-1919 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
    - Index, by subject, to minutes, 1898-1923 (Box 133:, Folder 2)
    - Corporate records and Board of Directors Minutes, 1899 (Box 133:, Folder 3)
    - Memo re: Buffalo Branch property (includes blueprint), August 4, 1926 (Box 133:, Folder 4)
    - List of Stockholders, 1915,1917,1918,192? (Box 133:, Folder 5-7)
    - Dividend List, 1925-1932 (Box 133:, Folder 8)
    - Verification from Secretary of State, 1951 (Box 133:, Folder 9)
  - American Brass Co. of Illinois
    - Photostatic copy of minutes, etc., 1927 (Box 133:, Folder Folder 1)
  - American Brass Co. of Ohio
    - Corporate record and original appointment of agent, 1935 (Box 133:, Folder Folder 1)
  - American Flask & Cap Co.
    - Misc., invoices, resignation of S.B. Teary, Jr., ca. 1870 (Box 133:, Folder Folder 1)
    - Anaconda American Brass: Corporate Records, 1965-19??
  - Ansonia Brass & Battery Company
    - Financial notes from ledger, 1858-1862 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
  - Ansonia Brass & Copper Co.
    - Minutes, 1869-1910 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
    - Corporate Documents (Articles of Association, etc.), 1869-1895 (Box 133:, Folder 2)
    - Executive Committee, notes, 1893-1899 (Box 133:, Folder 3)
    - Misc. statements, announcements, correspondence, 1905-1911 (Box 133:, Folder 4)
    - Misc. papers relating to directors meetings, 1880-1912 (Box 133:, Folder 5)
    - President's Report, 1903, 1907 (Box 133:, Folder 6)
    - Statement, 1873 (Box 133:, Folder 7)
  - Ansonia Clock Co.
    - Stockholders, 1913-1916 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
  - Ansonia Land & Water Power Co.
    - Dissolution of company, 1934 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
    - By-laws, report to IRS, stockholders, 1912, 1911, 1902 (Box 133:, Folder 2)
    - Misc. correspondence, 1904-1912 (Box 133:, Folder 3)
  - Benedict & Burnham Brass & Copper Co.
    - Annual Report, 1903 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
  - Benedict & Burnham Mfg. Co.
    - Salaries, 1905-1909 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
    - Papers relating to corporate record, 1905-1912 (Box 133:, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence re: Shareholders, 1887-1900 (Box 133:, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1865 (Box 133:, Folder 4)
  - Detroit Copper and Brass Rolling Mills
    - Bonds, Assets/Liabilities, balance sheets, etc., 1927 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
    - Proxy materials, 1927 (Box 133:, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, special meetings, 1927 (Box 133:, Folder 3)
    - Agreement with Anaconda Sales Co., 1927 (Box 133:, Folder 4)
  - French Manufacturing Co.
    - Items of stockholder interest, 1910-1929 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
    - Agreement to sell, 1907 (Box 133:, Folder 2)
    - Articles of Incorporation, By-laws, Financial Data, 1905-1910 (Box 133:, Folder 3)
  - Waterbury Brass Company
    - Brass Manufacturers' Meeting, 1881 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
    - Annual Statements, 1847-1853, 1886 (Box 133:, Folder 2)
    - Stockholder List, 1862, 1864, 1911 (Box 133:, Folder 3)
    - Papers relating to incorporation, 1861, 1865 (Box 133:, Folder 4)
    - Manhan Manufacturing Co. — annual statement, 1851 (Box 133:, Folder 5)
    - American Brass Association, Price Notices, 1901-1902 (Box 133:, Folder 6)
    - Items relating to stockholder meetings, 1910-1911 (Box 133:, Folder Folders 7-8)
    - Taxes, 1846, 1894 (Box 133:, Folder 9)
    - Transfer of bonds in probate, 1890, 1900 (Box 133:, Folder 10)
  - Waterbury Brass Goods Corp.
    - By-laws, 1934 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
    - Misc. correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 133:, Folder 2)
  - Waterbury Homes Corp.
    - Trial Balance, 1922 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
  - Wolcottville Brass Company
    - Agreement with J. Hungerford and I. Coe (stored in box with bound volumes), 1845 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified Companies
    - Inventory, misc. financial figures, ca. 1849 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
  - Old Trails Realty Company
    - Bylaws, minutes, stock certificates, 1953-1955 (Box 133:, Folder 1)
    - Bank statements, cancelled checks, 1953-1955 (Box 133:, Folder 2)